[Music]
welcome my name is baj Koto and my name
is monicaa and we together work at the
Microsoft Development Center in
Copenhagen working on business Central
and integration between business Central
and Power Platform and today
specifically we will be talking about
our new feature uh in our integration
with power automate a feature that
allows you to build flows using copilot
I will talk about Power Platform and AI
feature and of course our integration
with power automate and how you can now
use the new uh capability to create
flows so let's dive into this is into
this feature Power Platform already as
you know of different tools allowing you
to build um experiences without
development using lowco development
tools as they call it and it is already
infused with AI actually Power Platform
already started uh adding features
related to AI uh in
2019 we have multiple different features
right now in Power Platform and multiple
Integrations that exist uh to date and
of course the the the product that we'll
be looking at in this session is power
automate allowing you to build flows
build automations this tool is already
quite nicely integrated with business
Central and allows you to build approval
flows automated flows and custom actions
we have separate recording in this event
that talks about improvements that we
made in this particular area uh in this
this wave so please tune into that into
that recording when we talk to Partners
and our customers about how they use
business Central and power automate we
keep hearing about some challenges uh
first of all creators are offered a a
list of templates and as we know we have
plenty of those isn't that correct mon
yes we have more than 70 templates for
business Central so we have a lot but
still it is not enough it covers some
scenarios but not everything and of
course as an alternative you can start
from scratch you can build your flow but
it might be challenging you don't know
what where where you are looking uh what
you are looking for and especially if
you are connecting business Central to
different other systems you want to send
a notification to teams send an email uh
save something on SharePoint uh act when
someone added a new line to an Excel
file it is all perfectly possible and
easy to do in power automate but you
have to know where to start so this new
feature is allowing you to add a new
flow using just natural language imagine
creating a flow with copilot in power
automate built directly inside business
Central Let's uh talk about how it works
Monica can you explain what is needed in
order to create that flow yes this is a
very simple process so now we have a new
Option under the power automate group
that allows you to create flow using
co-pilot and power automate so the way
it starts is that the user starts by
describing what what is that what they
want to automate once they have
described in a natural language let's
say for example they want to automate
that whenever a item is created in
business Central you also create a new
item in a SharePoint list then this
input is given to the power automate and
then power automate suggest the flow
steps that are needed to create this
automation once power automate suggest
the flow steps so when a record is
created add an item in point then the
user can actually go ahead and fill the
necessary parameters that are needed and
complete the flow so it's such a simple
three-step
process super thanks a lot Monica and of
course we have video showing you how it
is done the best way is to see it in
action can we see a demo of course we
can so let's just go to the automate
menu and now we have a new action that
allows you to create flows using
co-pilot let's see how it looks
like so here you have an option to
describe what you want to automate and
you also have the examples but let's
just go
ahead and start typing the scenario so
in this case I want to say when a new
product is added in business Central
create a new item in the SharePoint
list then the power automate is
suggesting the steps to do this
flow let's go ahead and click next and
now it recognizes all the connections
that we need to run this flow so of
course for the business Central and for
SharePoint and the steps are suggested
so let's just go ahead and finish the
flow so then we just go ahead and fill
the parameters that are missing so we'll
select for example the marketing site
and and the products
list where we want to add an item
whenever a new item is added in business
Central and we'll give a
title and then we'll create flow as you
can see the workflow has been added
successfully let's see how the flow
looks in power
automate so this is the flow that has
been created using co-pilot and power
automate and as you can see the flow has
the steps that was suggested and all the
parameter that were filled and the flow
works fine we also have the co-pilot
chat so that you can use to add more
things in this flow if
needed and if you want you can also edit
Advanced parameters which were not
filled or not required while creating
the flow from copilot so that's how easy
it was to create a flow using
copilot thank you Monica we can't wait
to see what you guys will build with
this feature when it is available for
you later in this wave so what what is
important this feature is coming as
preview later in this wave later in 2024
it will be available for or initially
available for business Central uh set as
English as a language and for power
automate environments that are based in
USA but later on of course this will
change we will be adding this feature
making it available uh in other regions
as well and of course as always in this
event you have multiple other recording
that are relevant we have an a fantastic
recording about integration with power
platforms that we actually uh did
together uh we have also a a a session
about integration with data verse that
talks about the data verse virtual
tables also important for Power Platform
and we also have a session that talks
about changes in documentation and more
stuff around um around integration with
with third party systems as always
please go to our resources aka. msbc all
to find all the links to different uh
different tools and setups that you need
to cooperate with us uh send us ideas
using BC ideas uh work and talk to us
using Yammer join our open uh open
Office hour sessions uh every now and
then we're doing that for Power Platform
as well and of course if you are joining
us at directions and we will be able
talk to talk in person thank you very
much that was it for today thank you
very
much